This month, we're talking about open
door.
Open door.
Responsibility, uplifted kingdom.
Stewardship. So, that's what we're
talking about. And sometimes you may
think when we talk about stewardship,
we're talking about money, money, money,
money. But, stewardship is bigger than
that. Amen.
You are coming today is your stewarding
your time to come to worship God.
And so, we thank God. Today, I want to
talk about a call to steward revival.
A call to steward revival. We are
reading this verse because it is a
prayer that the church made
during a very challenging season of
their life. So, let me read from verse
23.
The Bible says, "On their release,
Peter and John went back to their own
people and reported all that the chief
priests and the elders had said to them.
When they heard this, that is when the
church heard this, they raised their
voices together in what?
In prayer to God. This is what they
said. "Sovereign Lord," they said, "You
made the heavens and the earth and the
sea and everything in them.
You spoke by the Holy Spirit through the
mouth of your servant, our father David.
Why do the nations rage and the peoples
plot in vain? The kings of the earth
rise up and the rulers band together
against the Lord and against his
anointed one.
Indeed, Herod and the and Pontius Pilate
met together with the Gentiles and the
people of Israel in this city to
conspire against your holy servant
Jesus, whom you anointed.
They did what your power and will had
decided beforehand should happen.
Now, Lord, consider their threats and
enable your servants to speak your word
with great boldness.
Stretch out your hand to heal
and perform signs and wonders through
the name of your holy servant Jesus."
After they prayed, the place where they
were meeting
was shaken and they were all filled with
the Holy Spirit and they spoke the word
of God boldly. All the believers were
one in heart and mind. No one claimed
that any of their possessions was their
own, but they shared everything they
had.
With great power, the apostles continued
to testify
to the resurrection of the Lord Jesus
and God's grace was at work powerfully
was powerfully at work in them all.
Verse 34, "that there were no needy
persons among them. For from time to
time, those who owned land or houses
sold them,
brought the money from the sales and to
the apostles." This is God's word and
God's people said,
We may be seated in God's uh presence
and all glory goes back to him.
Father, in Jesus' name,
may your word come forth
clearly. May you inspire us. May you
speak to our hearts. And Lord, even
those watching online, those in the
pavilion, those right here in person,
how we just bring ourselves at your
feet. May you speak to us in a very
special way. We give you all the glory
and all the praise because we have
prayed in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Last week,
I told you that this week I was going to
give you a card that is going to enable
us to position ourselves to pray
and especially to pray for revival. We
are entering into a season because at
the end of the month, we are going to
start the season revival season 10 week.
But, we want to engage in a time of
prayer. We have been praying. We are on
a 21-day prayer and fasting season. But,
also we want you to let you know that we
want to
band our resources, band our minds, come
bring them together focused so that we
can
um just
come before the Lord because God is
about to answer your prayer in a big
way.
I'm saying God is about to answer your
prayer in a big way.
One of the things we are taking
advantage of is this thing called number
seven.
Number seven is a very key number.
We are in the seventh month.
This is day 14.
First Sunday was number seven.
This Sunday is seven times two,
which is 14.
Next Sunday will be seven times three,
which will be what?
The day we are going to launch the
revival week will be seven times four,
which is what?
28. Number seven is a key number in the
Bible.
And I want you to know that God wants us
to use this open door. Some people call
it a portal or an open door
because it is a divinely set door to be
used.
Genesis chapter 2 verse 2 says this uh
concerning number seven. Tell your
neighbor, "There is something special
coming our way."
It says, "By the seventh day, God had
done what?"
Finished the work he had been doing. So,
on the seventh day, he rested from all
his work. Seven is a number of
completion. It is also a number of rest.
And I want you to know that God has been
working in terms of your issues
and you're going to have a rest
in this month.
In this season.
Hallelujah.
Hebrews chapter 4 verse 4 says this
again concerning number seven.
"For somewhere he has spoken about the
seventh day in these words,
'On the seventh day, God rested from all
his
works.'"
Now,
today, which day is today? Is it the
seventh day or is it Is it the first
day?
Okay, so let me ask you one more time.
Today, today is Sunday.
Now, the reason why it is Sunday is
because
um in terms of the calendars, we there
is what we call the Gregorian calendar.
And that calendar was given certain
names and so, Sunday was
given because of that time the Romans,
whoever they were, they were worshipping
the sun god.
Are we together?
That's why it is called Sun-
day.
Monday
was dedicated to the moon god.
That is why it's called Moon- day.
Hello.
On Monday.
Okay, so those are the names. Tuesday
and other things, Wednesday, Thursday
um dedicated to the god of Thor. If you
have ever heard of Thor, the god of
thunder.
Hallelujah.
All all that. Even the months, January,
February, those are the names. The
Jewish calendar, in terms of the Hebrew
calendar,
the seventh day, which is the Sabbath
day, it is which day of the week?
Saturday.
So, Sunday is not the Sabbath day. So,
look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, "Today is not the Sabbath
day."
Okay? So, if you are from Seventh-day
Adventist, you are a very happy person
to be able to hear what I've just said.
Amen. So, Saturday is the seventh day.
Sun-
week, it is the day Jesus Christ rose
from the dead.
So, today,
today is dedicated to Jesus who rose
from the dead. So, he rested.
Bwana asifiwe.
Are we getting that? So, the issue is
not should we worship on Saturday or
Sunday. The issue is that we should
worship every day. Bwana asifiwe. For
such the Father seeks to do what? To
worship him. So, seven is very key, very
important. We also find in another space
in the Bible that Jericho was brought
down when they were given instructions
to march
On the seventh day, they marched how
many times?
Seven times. That's number seven,
completion and rest. We together?
Elijah prayed for a boy
dead, Elijah
and after some time, the boy's body
became warm and he sneezed seven times.
On the seventh time, he woke up.
Hello.
Just talking to you about number seven.
Bwana asifiwe.
Another time, there was no there was
famine in the land for three and a half
years. Then Elijah prayed and Elijah put
his head between his knees and he
prayed. He told the servant, "Go check
if there's anything happened." He went
check, there was nothing. He went again
check, there was nothing. He went again,
checked there was nothing. On the
seventh time
he saw there was a cloud as small as a
man's fist, and Elijah said, "We better
start running because I hear the sound
of rain."
And the rain came. Seven, a number of
completion, and a number of rest, and a
number of breakthrough.
We also see that Naaman the leper
came from his country and came to the
man of God, and he was given one
instruction. Just go to the River
Jordan. Of course, by the way, River
Jordan was not a very clean river. It
was like Nairobi River. So, look at your
neighbor and tell your neighbor, "Amen."
It was not a swimming pool. It was not
something so nice. I have been to the
Jordan Jordan River. I've been to
Israel, Pastor Simon. You've been to
Israel. The Jordan River is a very just
a very normal river. Okay, flowing from
Mount Hermon, coming through Galilee,
flowing through Galilee, going to the
Dead Sea.
Naaman is given just one instruction. Go
deep yourself how many times?
Seven times.
Now, he was quite an arrogant man
because he was a commander of the army.
First of all, he was very upset that
Elisha could not see him. And then later
he he went. He dipped himself once, he
came up, nothing. Dips himself another
time, nothing.
Going, nothing. On the sixth time, he
could he was about to go home
because nothing had happened. But the
instruction was what?
Seven times. On the seventh time, he
just went in. I think by that time, I
don't think he had faith, Pastor Simon.
There was no faith there. He says,
"Anyway, let me do it. It's in seven. In
about two more days, it's over." He went
in, and when he came out, from the top
of his head to the tips of his toes, he
was clean.
God can give you you a miracle like
that.
May this month be that your portion in
Jesus' name.
In Jesus' name.
And so even as I was praying and I was I
told you this last week that
um God enabled me to come up with an
idea and say, "Let's let's mobilize the
entire church to pray."
And so, I was able to put together a
card which each one of you is going to
get, and I'm going to explain it to you.
This card is called the sevenfold prayer
commitment.
And it's mobilizing us to pray because
revival is coming your way.
In Jesus' name.
I want to ask the ushers to help
distribute those cards to you right now.
You're going to get a card each if you
haven't gotten. Have you gotten one?
Who doesn't have?
Why did you say yes?
Okay. A card is coming your way. As that
card comes your way, we also have Pastor
Simon, we have put a link on our
website,
and that link is going out to all those
who are online. So, if you are online, a
card is coming your way in Jesus' name.
We've printed quite a number of cards.
We want all of you to get it. Not get
church is getting it.
Not get Eastgate because we want all of
us to engage, and it is called a
sevenfold prayer commitment. I want to
look at it. On that first page, it says
this.
And by the way,
this card can be folded. All right?
It can be folded. Tell your neighbor,
"Folded."
If you don't want to fold it, it's okay.
So, don't fold it. There are people who
do not like folding things.
But you can fold it so you can put it in
your bag and things like that. On the
first page, just look at it as I read
it. It says the sevenfold prayer
commitment. And then down there it's
written, "The Lord Jesus Christ invites
you to the open door of what?"
Of answered prayer. And I want us to
read that verse together in John. Here
we go. One to go.
In that day, you will no longer ask me
anything.
Very truly, I tell you, my Father will
give you whatever you ask in my name.
Until now, you have not asked for
anything.
And and you will receive, and your joy
of answered prayer will be complete.
Now, it is important for me to just
clarify that because sometimes we miss
what that statement uh refers to. So,
Pastor Simon will help me. Pastor Simon
is going to be Jesus. So, Pastor Simon,
come here. So, tell your neighbor,
"Pastor Simon is Jesus for today."
Bwana asifiwe.
And I want to ask um Alex, why don't you
come up? Alex is going to be Father, the
father of Jesus.
Or can we switch?
Okay, they have decided that we switch.
So, you're going to be
Father is going to be Jesus. Amen.
Uh does the Father look like the Son
look like Jesus? Does the Son look like
the Father?
By faith. Just tell your neighbor, "By
faith."
Okay. So, we need to just say this. It
says this. Now, look at your card. It
says, "In that day, you will no longer
ask me anything." In other words, this
is Jesus, and Jesus saying, "In that
day." There is a particular day. They
will not ask Jesus anything.
Now, the interesting thing that is in
our prayer, we always ask Jesus many
things.
We are always talking to Jesus. We are
praying to Jesus. Now, you can have
fellowship with Jesus, but when it comes
to kingdom transactions,
you talk to the Father.
Hallelujah.
In that day was a very special day. That
day was this. Jesus Christ, when he was
talking about this in John, he was
telling them,
"I am going to die.
I'm going to be buried. I'm going to be
raised from the dead. I am going to
ascend to the right hand of God the
Father. At that time, my name will be
lifted up,
and I'll have authority in heaven, on
earth, and under the earth. On that day,
you will no longer ask me anything.
But you'll ask the Father because in
that day, I will have received
authority.
My name will now be a signatory to
transact kingdom business for you."
Hallelujah.
So, don't ask Jesus for
to him.
Come to who?
The Father.
Now, they are one, but it is the Father
you are addressing. So, Jesus is saying
in that card,
"In that day, you will no longer ask me
anything." So, look at your neighbor.
Tell your neighbor, "Don't ask Jesus
anything."
Father
will do what?
Do not
This name is powerful.
of Mary, the mother of Jesus.
That name is not a signatory to transact
kingdom business.
Jesus
Every nation
had in heaven.
He said there's only one name.
Amen.
And the Father listens to that name.
You do? Yes.
The Father is speaking. Can you tell us
some things, Father? Okay.
Yes, I'm just saying, I listen
to the name of my son.
Yes.
Then the next verse. By the way, I'm in
the middle of my message.
I'm actually preaching. I'm already in
So, don't don't don't try to wait until
you say something about introduction.
There's no introduction. I'm in the
middle of my message.
Hello. Then it says, "Until now, you
have done what?"
You have not asked for anything in my
name. You see, Jesus had not died. So,
by then, they had not asked in this
name. This name had not been
released.
Are we together?
And then he says,
"But now, ask,
and you will
Who are you asking?
Ask and you will receive, and your joy
of answered prayer will be what?
Will be complete."
And so, when you open that card, one of
the things we're going to do, okay? So,
here is a card while we are talking here
before you go down.
One of the things we are going to deal
with is those seven things. Number one,
we have seven prayer requests. So,
you're going to begin asking God. There
are seven things I'm going to be praying
for. Secondly, seven people for prayer.
So, there are seven people you're going
to begin to say, "These ones I'm going
to pray for."
You decide who those are.
Help God also help you decide who they
are because let me tell you this. The
Father is going to answer your prayer.
Until now, you have asked nothing. The
Seven people. Maybe they're in your
family, maybe they're in your
neighborhood, maybe they're at your
workplace, maybe they're out of the
country, but remember seven people.
And then you're going to pray for seven
weeks. Tell your neighbor, "Seven
weeks."
On the 28th of this month, because next
Sunday I'll be talking to the other
people who will not have come
today. So, they'll come next Sunday and
I'll tell them.
So, that on the 28th, when we are
launching, come with your card.
So, turn to the the other neighbor who
just didn't hear you.
Hear me.
Tell your neighbor, "Come with your
card."
On that day, we are going to re- take
all our cards and we are going to have a
united corporate prayer. And we're going
to agree.
One agreement, that Father, what we have
written,
make it happen.
And make it happen in the next seven
weeks. That day starts the seven weeks,
on the 28th. So, we have that week of
revival, then the next week, next week,
if you count seven weeks, we'll have
ended in September. I believe it's
either the first or the second week of
September.
That week of September in the Jewish
calendar is their last month and they're
starting their new year September the
23rd.
Hallelujah.
And so, get ready for the new year. So,
tell your neighbor, "Get ready for the
new year."
And then and and so, every week as we
pray,
uh when you finish a week, tick. That
those boxes are for you to tick, not for
you to color, for you to tick.
All right? You either tick or you put an
X and say, "We have done that." Week
one, week two. This is just to keep you
focused.
People just need to be focused. And
then, as you pray, there are seven
expectations and they are written there.
What are you expecting God to do during
those seven weeks? Number one, God's
divine will
revealed. Okay? God's will will be re-
revealed. Do you want to know God's
will?
So, for example, if some of your prayer
requests are this, "Lord Jehovah God, I
want my husband to be saved." Okay? So,
that's your prayer, "My husband to be
saved." But your expectation is that his
will will be revealed.
Not done.
Revealed.
Okay? It will be what? Revealed. So, as
you're praying for your husband, as God
begins to re- reveal his will, part of
the salvation of your husband is this,
God's will will be revealed to you that
you need to start treating your husband
nicely.
Hallelujah.
That is part of him getting saved. But
his will for you for that time is that
you start treating your husband nicely.
Bwana asifiwe. Start talking to him
nicely. Bwana asifiwe.
Start massaging his head in Jesus' name.
I'm telling you, God's will will be
revealed. Not done, revealed.
Because some of you, your focus is so
much on your particular desire, you
don't care what God wants to be done.
So, God's will will be revealed. God, I
need this job. Lord Jehovah, give me
this job. And so, then God will reveal
his will that that particular job you're
asking is not what he wants you to have.
Because there's a a better job that he
has in store for you.
And he will still you give you that job,
but not the one you're actually asking.
His will will be revealed. Are you
hearing what I'm saying?
Because sometimes you can come before
God and he's hasn't answered your
prayer, so upset and everything, but you
do not are not waiting for God's will to
be revealed. Secondly,
God's divine provision manifested. God
will manifest his provision. Number
three, God's divine grace
will be realized. That's what we've been
talking about. Number four, God's power
unleashed. There are some things and
some obstacles that are holding you that
you cannot push by yourself. God is
going to release his power and it's
going to smash those walls in ways you
cannot imagine. So, that's your
expectation. Tell your neighbor, "These
are our expectations."
Number five, God's wisdom aligned. In
other words, God will give you his will
uh his wisdom and you'll align to it.
You'll align to it.
By wisdom a house
is built. By understanding it is
established. By knowledge its rooms are
filled with precious treasures. And
number six, God's divine presence will
be experienced. I'm telling you, you
will experience God's presence in a very
powerful way.
Moses said, "Lord, if you don't go with
us,
we will not go." God's presence will be
revealed. And then number seven, God's
divine transformation will be what?
Actualized. Now, those are the
expectations. You have requests,
you have people you're praying, you have
time to pray, and then you have
the seven expectations. And then on the
last page, there it says,
uh we're reading it together. Want to
go?
God is a God of covenant.
What he says, he will do.
What he declares, he will establish.
What he designs, he will create. What he
promises, he will fulfill.
Believe it. Receive it. Take it. It is
your portion in the now. In the name of
Jesus, it is sealed. Amen.
Come on, let's bless the Lord
and thank him for that.
So, I have given these instructions
clearly because I want you to to follow
them.
Bwana asifiwe.
I want you to follow them. I will repeat
some of them next week, but we have that
link online because you can pass it on,
sambaza it on WhatsApp,
put it wherever you want to go because
we are not just asking people in
Parklands to pray, we are asking God's
people wherever they are to do what?
To pray in Jesus' name. So, Father, we
are glad that we can talk to you
in that signatory name, Jesus Christ.
And we know when we pray
to you in that name,
we shall have whatever we ask.
And you have what it takes.
Father, do you have whatever it takes?
Tell them.
Our heavenly Father has Okay, I do.
I do whatever I mean, I have what it
takes.
Uh when prayer comes through the name of
my son, Jesus.
Amen.
Tukwapigie makofi.
Thank you, guys.
Bless you. Bless you. Bless you.
A call to steward revival.
And so, part of this stewarding is
praying.
There are things God does not do without
us doing what?
Praying.
And Pastor Simon, when King Solomon had
finished building the temple,
Second Chronicles, chapter six and
chapter seven,
Solomon did a very serious prayer
because the temple needed to be
dedicated. And the temple is us. It is
the church of Jesus Christ.
Before I get there, because I'm going
I'm getting there, is
when the church prayed in the book of
Acts,
it was because something had happened
that they had received.
And they needed to recognize they had
received it.
And as I'm talking to you, let me tell
you this, there's something you have
received.
In the book of Acts chapter three,
chapter two, they received the power of
the Holy Spirit.
But in chapter three, they want to
exercise what they have received.
And so, they have a first assignment as
a church. Let me read those verses. Acts
three, verse one.
The Bible says that Peter and John are
on their way to the temple to pray. So,
let me read those verses very quickly.
One day, Peter and John were going up to
the temple at the time of prayer.
Remember, it was at the time of what?
Of prayer, at 3:00 in the afternoon.
Now, a man was lame from birth was being
carried
to the temple gate called Beautiful,
where he was put every day
to beg from those going into the temple
courts.
When he saw Peter and John about to
enter, he asked them for money. He was
used to asking this thing. And
sometimes, let me tell you this, we can
be used to in be in a certain position
for so long until it is a normal
position.
It is so normalized that we think that's
how God wants things to work.
And so, this beggar was not expecting a
miracle. Nothing was going to change
that particular day, but let me tell you
this, God had already located him.
And I want to say this that God has a
located you.
And God has located this country, Kenya,
even in this season and time.
The Bible says when he looked when Peter
looked
Peter then looked straight at him, as
did John. Both of them looked at him,
but it's only Peter who said, "Look at
us." So, the man gave them his
attention, expecting to get something
from them.
Then Peter said,
"Silver or gold, I do not have.
What you are expecting is not what I'm
about to give to you.
Silver and gold I do not have.
And then he says, "But what I do have
I give you." Then he said something, "In
the name of Jesus Christ." I don't know
if you're getting what I'm saying.
He was now exercising that signature
that they have been given.
And that's what I want to let you know
that as we begin to pray, as we begin to
trust God, don't trust in your ability.
Trust in the signature.
Don't trust in your cleverness. Don't
trust Don't try to impress God with
anything. Use the name.
That is the password.
And that password has not changed.
In the name
of Jesus Christ of Nazareth,
walk.
The Bible says in the next verse,
taking him by the right hand, he helped
him up, and instantly the man's feet and
ankles became strong. He jumped to his
feet and began to walk. Then he went
with them into the temple courts,
walking and jumping and praising God.
Let me tell you this, somebody is about
to shift their level.
They're no longer going to be begging,
they're going to jump up. They're going
to walk, and they're going to shout and
praise the name of Jesus Christ. Your
miracle is just around the corner.
I'm saying your miracle is just about
around the corner.
And it is not based on your
spirituality, it is based on the name of
Jesus Christ.
When the people started wondering, "Oh,
how do how could you do this? How could
you say that?" Verse 16, 15 and 16,
Peter is now giving a reason to what
just happened.
He says in verse 15, "You killed the
author of life." And Pastor Simon,
sometimes when I read statements like
that, it is funny because how can you
kill the author of life?
How do you kill him? You can't kill him.
But anyway, you killed the author of
life, but God raised him from the dead.
We are witnesses of this. And then he
said, "By faith in the name of Jesus,
this man whom you see and know was made
strong.
It is Jesus' name and the faith that
comes through him that has completely
healed him as you all can do what can
see." Let me say this, your
breakthroughs are only going to come
because you invoke the name of Jesus
Christ.
Not just like you're finishing a prayer,
because for some of us, we are so used
because every time we pray, we finish in
the name of Jesus. We don't have the
revelation that we are invoking a
signature, we are invoking a name that
has destroyed Satan in heaven on earth
and under the earth. Jesus' name is
above every name.
And so when you call on the name of
Jesus, as you begin to call to steward
this name to revival, remember this, the
name behind that revival is the name of
Jesus Christ.
And so, take it back into the Old
Testament.
In the Old Testament, Solomon
is preparing to dedicate the temple, and
he prepares God's people, and then he
says this,
much later, actually it is not him who
said it, it's now God who said it. After
he dedicated all this, then God says
this, and I want to read that verse, 2
Chronicles 7:14.
The Bible says this,
2 Chronicles.
Can we read that together? Here we go.
If my people who are called
and seek my face and turn from their
wicked ways,
heaven, and I will forgive
And God is saying, "This is what you're
going to do.
If you do it, this is what I'm going to
do."
Chapter 6 of verse 12,
King Solomon was praying. And I pray
that all of us will learn to pray like
King Solomon. He says this,
"Then Solomon stood before the altar of
the Lord in front of the whole assembly
of Israel and spread out his hands.
And he said, 'Now
he had made Now he had made a bronze
platform five cubits long, five cubits
wide, and three cubits high.
And had placed it in the center of the
outer court. He stood on the platform
and then knelt down before the whole
assembly of Israel and spread out his
hands towards heaven, and this is what
he said.
He said, 'Lord, the God of Israel, there
is no God like you in heaven or on
earth.
You who keep your covenant of love with
your servants, who continue
wholeheartedly in your way.
You have kept your promise to your
servant David, my father.
With your mouth you have promised and
with your hand you have fulfilled it as
it is today.
Now, Lord, the God of Israel,
keep for your servant David, my father,
the promises you made to him when you
said, "You shall never fail to have a
successor to sit before me on the throne
of Israel, if only your descendants are
careful in all they do to walk before me
according to my law as you have done."
And now, Lord, the God of Israel, let
your word that you promised your servant
David come true.
But
but will God really dwell on earth with
humans? The heavens, even the highest
heavens cannot contain you.
How much less this temple I have built.
Yet, Lord my God, give attention to your
servant's prayer and his plea for mercy.
Hear the cry and the prayer that your
servant is praying in your presence.
May your eyes be open towards this
temple day and night, this place of
which you said you'd put your name
there. You'd put your name there. May
you hear the prayer your servant prays
towards this place."
Let me tell you this, God answers
prayer.
I'm saying God answers prayer.
So, second the next chapter, chapter 7
verse 1. Let me tell you this, God will
come through. Listen to what he says in
chapter 7 verse 1 to 5.
When Solomon finished praying,
what happened?
I pray that fire will come down.
The fire of revival will come down. When
Solomon finished praying, fire came down
from heaven and consumed the burnt
offering and the sacrifices, and the
glory of the Lord filled the temple. The
priests could not enter the temple of
the Lord because the glory of the Lord
filled it.
When all the Israelites saw the fire
coming down and the glory of the Lord
above the temple, they knelt on the
pavement with their faces to the ground,
and they worshipped and gave thanks to
the Lord saying, "He is good.
His love endures forever."
This is what they did. So, God answered
their prayer in an amazing way. Then God
gave the next instruction. Same chapter
verse 14. So, God now is now speaking,
and this is what God says. And then God
says in verse 14 in that chapter, "If my
people" So, he starts there, and he
says, "If my people" All right, can I
get second That's what If my people,
he's saying, "Hey, you have dedicated
this temple, I have answered." And then
now he says, "If my people
who are called by my name will humble
themselves and pray and seek my face and
turn from their wicked ways, then I will
hear from heaven, I will forgive their
sins, I will heal their land."
Ladies and gentlemen, God wants us to
steward revival by prayer.
And in this chapter, just those that one
verse, because I want to use that verse
now to summarize the message.
God is saying, number one, he's calling
for a people.
So, tell your neighbor, he's calling for
a people.
And then he says, he wants us to have a
position, okay? Our people,
our position, and thirdly, our purpose.
So, tell your neighbor, our people,
our position,
our purpose.
Hallelujah.
Can you remember that?
Now, what people is he talking about? He
says, "If my
people called by my name." Pastor Simon,
there's just one people that God is
dealing with. And he's saying, at that
time he was talking about the
Israelites. Today he's talking about the
church.
He's talking about the church. We are
his people.
We are the one who have an authorized
the name that we can use.
One time another guy tried to use that
name. He said, "In the name of Jesus
whom Paul preaches, come out." What
happened?
You don't want to know.
Bad things
happened. Because you cannot use
somebody else's signature or even for
forge it, because let me tell you this,
the justice of God will catch up with
you.
And so God is saying, "Use my son's
name." You And he The father said it's
right here. Use my father my son's name,
you'll go through. His people are the
church. You are the church.
Let me tell you this,
the solution for this country is not
coming from state house.
It is coming from the church of Jesus
Christ, and you are the church. You
carry the name of Jesus Christ.
Mhm? Just look at your neighbor one more
time and say, "Pastor Ambrose is talking
to about you.
You are the church.
And so God is saying, "If my people who
are called by my name." So God is
saying, "The church is very powerful."
In Matthew 16,
when Peter said, "You are the Christ,
the son of the living God."
Jesus later said in verse 18,
that chapter, verse 18. This is what
Jesus said, "And I tell you you are
who?" Peter. "And on this rock
I will build what?"
My church. "And the gates of Hades will
not overcome it."
Hallelujah. Then verse 19, "I will give
you the keys
of the kingdom. And one of these keys is
the key of praying in the name of
Jesus."
"I will give you the keys of the kingdom
of heaven. Whatever you bind on earth
will be bound in heaven. And whatever
you loose on earth will be loosed in
in heaven." And that is what Pastor
Simon Peter used on that day. He said,
"Uh what I have received, I give to
you."
In the name of Jesus.
Rise up and walk.
I want to talk to a mother here.
Your child suddenly develops a fever
that hits goes to 30, 32, 33. The fever
is not coming down. You're wondering
what to do. Let me tell you this. Look
at that fever in the face and tell that
fever,
"In the name of Jesus Christ, I command
you fever to come out and temperatures
to normalize." Let me tell you, you'll
be shocked because the father
will make it happen for you.
Hallelujah.
Yes. Come on, let's give God a big hand.
Now sometimes Pastor Simon, there are
mothers who do that and nothing happens.
The fever is still going.
And let me tell you this,
if that is happening,
just
give that child Panadol
because your faith has not reached that
level.
Because let me tell you this, there are
some people who suffer because they
don't know that their faith has never
reached that stage. In fact, they are
praying, but inside their hearts they
are saying, "I eat a panicky."
So your faith is so small that you don't
have anything. So go to hospital, take
Panadol, do whatever you need to do.
Don't feel guilty about it.
Tell your neighbor, "We are growing."
And some of us just need to grow. Uh I
remember I remember
In fact, I don't remember because I was
going about to say I remember when I was
born.
I don't remember.
Uh
But I was going to say, you know, I
don't know if I I crawled at the
beginning. I don't know if I was carried
for some time. But one thing my mother
tells me that I suckled her breast
for nearly 3 years.
Thank you, Jesus.
I was the firstborn. Uh so everywhere I
would go run run run, then I would come
back, jump on her lap and and enjoy my
breakfast and
and my mother did not know how to stop
me.
So somehow my mother caught um
chickenpox.
And they used to pack up people white.
And so there's a day I woke up and I
found she was painted white.
As I was about to take my breakfast, I
said in my share hubble.
That is how I stopped suckling.
Hallelujah.
But I was not talking about I was not
talking about talking about suckling. I
was talking about
the day I stood up for the first time to
do what?
To walk. And you know that people
struggle and they think that walking is
easy. You know, you walk and it is easy.
And the parents are getting very they
get very excited
the day they see you walking. They say,
"Daddy daddy, I don't know how to
So they start talking in tongues.
And the baby is wondering what the mama
is saying. And they are trying to get
where the mother is and they don't know
how to walk. And they take the first
step like this and they hit ground.
Boom.
The mother doesn't say, "I rebuke you in
the name of Jesus."
No. Mother lifts the baby up and goes
back up and says,
And the baby tries for the first time he
walks,
then the next time he walks,
then the next time, then he falls, boom.
Let me tell you this.
That was child abuse.
Thank God somebody discovered something
called
walkers.
Hallelujah.
We were saved from falling down and
rising up. But let me tell you this,
there are sometimes you can use the name
of Jesus and nothing happens. Another
time you need the name of Jesus, nothing
happens. Don't worry. Stand up and keep
trying. Boom, stand up and keep trying.
Keep trying.
But it is if my people who are called by
my name.
So sometimes you'll be praying about
this prayer request that you have,
nothing seems to happen. You've already
ticked week one, week two, week three,
nothing is happening. My friend, keep
believing.
Keep trusting.
This God will surprise you and shock you
when one day you say in the name of
Jesus before you even finish in the
name, your miracle has come.
But it's not just our people he's
talking about. He's talking about our
position. There is a position. He says,
"If my people do two things, humble
themselves and pray."
That's the position.
And sometimes God has been waiting us to
position ourselves. We're not
positioning ourselves. We are not
humble.
We are not praying.
The opposite of humble is what?
Pride.
We are proud. We cannot pray. We are
thinking of how we can do this thing in
our own way. We are looking for somebody
we can call who can make this come
through. We are thinking of everything
else except humbling ourselves and say,
"God, this I cannot do. This I'm not
able to manage. God, I humble myself.
I humble myself." And let me tell you
this, pride comes in so many ways.
Pride.
The way I am proud is very different
from the way Pastor Simon is
proud.
And I'm talking about pride
not in the positive way, but pride in
the negative way, arrogance. You know,
feeling that you are the one who can
make it happen.
And let me tell you this,
you think the people in the world are
proud. Let me tell you this, it is the
people who are in church that are very
proud.
Now let me talk to the others on this
side.
It's the people who are in church that
are very proud. And let me tell you
this, God wants to deal with your pride.
He wants to position you to position
yourself to be in the right place so
that when you are positioned right, you
are his person, you are positioned
right. King Solomon had to go down on
his knees. He had to lift up his hands.
Even though he was Even though he was a
king, he humbled himself. The Bible says
that Jesus also humbled himself.
The Bible says in Philippians chapter 2.
Let me read those verses. Verse 5,
"Jesus, even though he was the son of
God, had to position himself." The Bible
says Philippians chapter 2 verse 5,
let me just read that. "In your
relationships with one another, have the
same mindset as Christ Jesus,
who being in very nature as who?
As God did not consider equality with
God something to be used to his own
advantage. Rather, he made himself
nothing by taking the very nature of a
servant,
being made in human likeness and being
found in appearance as a man, he did
what?
He humbled himself by becoming obedient
to death,
even death on a cross.
Therefore, God exalted him to the
highest place and gave him the name that
is above every name, that at the name of
Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven
and on earth and under the and under the
earth, and every tongue acknowledge that
Jesus Christ is Lord to the glory of God
the Father." Jesus positioned himself
and he prayed.
He humbled himself. And so during these
weeks as we talk about prayer,
if God shows you something of pride,
just confess it. Just say it by the way,
God, in this area of my life, I've been
very proud. Just humble yourself. Let
God forgive you, then let God lift you
up.
Hallelujah.
Bwana asifiwe.
Just look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, "I can discern pride in you."
Now you turn to that neighbor and tell
them, "I can also discern big pride in
you."
Just tell your neighbor, "By the way,
all of us are proud."
Seriously.
I'm proud.
Can be proud by the the kind of car you
drive,
the kind of places you go to.
Without knowing, you're just proud.
Hello.
And God is saying, "Hey, that position
you are in, I cannot answer your
prayers."
And sometimes you just need to humble
yourself. Husbands,
humble yourself
when your wife tells you something
and you say
I know where I'm going.
I said, "But we just passed where you
were supposed to turn."
Are you the one driving or is it me?
You know, there are some men who cannot
be taught by women.
A woman stands up to preach and you walk
out.
Hello. Say a woman cannot teach me.
Who knows that God is using that
particular woman to teach you because
God wants you to be humble.
Why are you quiet?
Some of you are just proud.
But God says, "If my people who are
called by my name humble themselves and
pray."
I have my own pride, so I'm not I'm not
just speaking to you. I have my own
pride and so I have to come to God
during these weeks and say, "God, reveal
the pride in my life." And when God
reveals it, I just humble myself. I say,
"Lord, forgive me." And I pray and God
opens those. In other words, we are
seeking for the position that will
release the revival we are talking
about.
Hallelujah.
Yes. But let me finish by saying this.
There's a purpose. Tell your neighbor
there's a purpose.
And so there's a people, there's a
position, there's a purpose and the
purpose is simple.
If my people who are called by my name
humble themselves and pray, and then he
says, "Seek
my face
and then turn
from their wicked ways." Who who who Who
should turn from their wicked ways?
Who should turn from their wicked ways?
God's
people.
Because it is God's people because of
their wickedness and because of the
wicked things they are not passing
refusing to release, their pipe, their
channel is blocked.
And God's blessings cannot pass through
because of this wickedness. Some of us
are thinking the people who are wicked
you all are
the church, we are wicked.
We are the ones who cause all kinds of
problems.
Hello.
We are wicked.
So turn. Tell your neighbor, "Turn."
Turn is simple. Turn does not mean you
you you you you you are you are
remorseful. The issue is not remorseful.
You know, when people say, "Turn." The
word repent does not mean being sorry.
It doesn't mean saying, "Oh yo yo yo yo
yo yo."
Yo yo yo yo yo yo yo yo yo yo yo. No,
no, no.
Repent means you are going this side and
then you did what? Turned.
Hello.
You are goggling and goggling and
goggling and goggling so much whiskey
and one day, instead of you goggling the
whiskey, you poured the whiskey in the
sink.
That is turn.
Turn turn turn.
Turn means you are married, you have a
wife,
but every time you drive and you're
seeing slay queens, you're saying,
Turn means
stop doing that. Do it to your wife.
It means turn turn turn.
Stop having mpango wa
and it happens in church.
Right here.
Oh, but Ambrose, you know, this one
always listens to me. When I go home, I
just hear
I'm I'm so tired of hearing
This one comes and says, "Sweetie,
can I massage
your hairless head?"
Yes, please. You mean
at home.
So let me say to that wife who goes on
doing
Please also you turn.
Turn.
No wonder your husband is always running
away.
Before even has even left the car,
you're all already talking to him.
Yani, that is This is the time you're
coming. I know where you're coming from.
In fact, you're not eating today.
Just go back where you came from. For
sure the husband goes back where he came
from.
In fact, you've given him permission.
He's so happy.
Turn means you do what?
Turn. Don't don't try to go around in
circles. Just turn. But it is such a
habit. Yes, you can change a habit.
I'm just giving you examples.
Bwana asifiwe.
But they they are just
extreme ones, but
there are there are others where you
just lie. Yani, you lie. You lie. You
exaggerate.
You lie. It's a habit.
But let me tell you this.
It only takes for a key
to open a door. That key just needs to
do what? Turn.
Bwana asifiwe.
You have your challenges. I have my own
challenges. Bwana asifiwe.
Yes.
Even these challenges of seeing people
around kitambo. You know, one time I'm
driving down Valley Road and I'm driving
and Martha is with me.
And so I see I see this creation of God
across the road.
So you know, you see them and you act as
if you have not seen them. Uh but you
pass, but you continue seeing them
through the rear
the rear mirror.
Martha nakwambia, "What are you trying
to do?"
I said, "I was just observing God's
creation and the beauty that is in the
world today."
Tell your neighbor, "No temptation has
overtaken you that is not common to
man."
God is faithful.
He will not let you be tempted beyond
your strength. All I'm saying is this,
turn.
Turn from your wicked ways. Then the
Bible says, "Then, after all those
things,
then will I hear from heaven,
forgive their sins
and heal their land."
I believe this nation is ripe for
revival.
Hallelujah.
Yes, if God's people can just begin to
believe God and
be a people position themselves rightly
and purpose to seek God, I'm telling you
something tremendous will happen.
I want to read one more verse, but I
want to read it when all of us are
standing.
Jeremiah 29
verse 11.
The Bible says this.
And we are reading it together, by the
way. One to go.
For I know the plans I have for you,
declares the Lord.
Plans to prosper you and not to harm
you.
Plans to give you hope and a future.
Then you will call on me and come and
pray to me. And I will listen to you.
You will seek me and find me when you
seek me with all your heart.
I will be found by you, declares the
Lord,
and will bring you back from captivity.
Amen.
God will do that. Why don't you give him
a big hand?
So as I prepare to pray,
what particular part of this message are
you going to remember?
Turn.
That's not all I was talking about.
Three things.
Number one,
our people. Number two,
our position. Number three,
our purpose. That's what I was talking
about.
So don't go out at at the parking and
say, "By the way, God spoke to us." What
did he say? Turn.
Somebody's wondering, "Turn from where?"
But I hope you have received the word.
If you have, give God a big hand and
tell him, "Thank you."
Hallelujah.
And the seven expectations,
God's divine will revealed.
God's divine provision manifested.
God's divine grace realized.
God's divine power unleashed. God's
divine wisdom aligned, God's divine
presence experienced, and God's divine
transformation actualized. May that be
your portion.
Now, give God another big hand.
Amen.
Let's pray. Father, we thank you.
And we honor you, and we give all the
glory to you.
There's no God like you.
There's no king like you.
And Father, even as we are positioning
ourselves in this season of prayer, we
know that revival
comes from your hand.
But it comes from your hand
when your people, who are called by your
name,
humble themselves and pray,
and seek your face, and turn from their
wicked ways.
And dear Lord, as they do that, as we do
that, as Pastor Ambrose does his part,
Lord, because I'm part of your people,
and as Ambrose humbles himself, as
Ambrose prays,
as Ambrose
turns from his wicked ways,
that God seeks you and turns from his
wicked ways, then will you hear from
heaven,
forgive his sins, and heal his land.
Father God, I thank you
because in this season, we are going to
experience breakthroughs,
amazing breakthroughs.
The things that could not work will
start working,
walking and leaping and praising God.
That's the picture I have
of this church
and God's people in this church.
Lord, start with us,
right here in Parklands,
right here where we are standing.
Dear Lord, you know us. We will not go
around finding out who else is wicked.
No. It is us.
It is me.
And so, Father, we bless you.
Help us to handle our pride.
And Lord, because it blocks so many
things in our lives,
may we humble ourselves, and may we
pray.
And so, Lord, I say thank you because I
know as this church takes this position,
it is through us you're going to bring
revival.
So, all glory goes back to you.
Thank you for hearing our prayer
because we have prayed in the name of
the Father, and in the name of the Son,
and in the name of the Holy Spirit. And
God's people say
Do you believe that?
Come on, let's give God a big hand.
Amen.
And that card says, "God is a God of
covenant.
What he says,
he will do. What he declares,
he will establish. What he designs,
he will create. What he promises,
he will fulfill. May that be your
portion.
Amen.
Are you glad you came?
I'm glad I came. What a nice feel.
Tell your neighbor, "Today is your
turning point."
In Jesus' name.
Now, look at your neighbor, and tell
your neighbor, "Our Pastor Ambrose is
about to bless and release his
blessing."
So, lift up your hand as we pray.
Father, in the name that is above every
name, it is my pleasure to bless your
people, those online, those in the
pavilion, those right here in person.
And I decree and declare this blessing
in the name of Jesus. And I decree and
declare it, and I say, "May the Lord
bless you.
May the Lord make his face to shine upon
you.
May the Lord be gracious to you. May the
Lord lift up his countenance upon you. I
decree and declare that your Monday is
blessed. Your Tuesday is blessed. Your
Wednesday is blessed. Your Thursday is
blessed. Your Friday is blessed. Your
Saturday is blessed. Sunday, you're
coming back with a testimony in the name
of Jesus Christ. In the name of Jesus
Christ.
You are blessed when you come in.
You're blessed when you go out. You're
blessed when you rise up. You're blessed
when you sit down. Your children are
blessed. Your children's children are
blessed. The work of your hands is
blessed. You're blessed in the name of
the Father, and the Son, and the Holy
Spirit. And God's people say
Amen. Amen. Amen. Amen.
Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, "Surely goodness
and mercy
shall follow you
all the days of your life.
And you shall dwell in the house of the
Lord
forever
and ever.
And there's nothing the devil can do
about it."
You are blessed
to be a blessing.
You are favored
to be favorable.
You are lifted
to lift others.
This is your portion.
And the devil cannot take it from you.
And now, may the grace of our Lord Jesus
Christ, and the love of God, and the
fellowship of the Holy Spirit be with us
now and forevermore. Amen. Have a great
week.